Finding Aid for Center for the Education of Women (University of Michigan) publications, 1962-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Center for the Education of Women (University of Michigan) publications 1962-2004
University of Michigan. Center for the Education of Women.
975 Bimu C 484 2
Center for the Education of Women publications include miscellaneous bibliographies, brochures, calendars, flyers, journals, and proceedings. Also includes newsletters such as Cornerstone and Newsletter: Center for Continuing Education of Women; reports documenting the history of CEW such as Center for the Education of Women: 30 Year Anniversary Report, 1964-1994 and publications describing CEW library holdings and materials from the Women in Science Program.
2.5 linear feet in 3 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor no. 6885 )
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The record group is open without restriction.
See the finding aid for the Center for the Education of Women (CEW) records for the unit history.
Center for the Education of Women publications include miscellaneous bibliographies, brochures, calendars, flyers, journals, and proceedings. Also included are newsletters such as Cornerstone and Newsletter: Center for Continuing Education of Women; reports documenting the history of CEW such as Center for the Education of Women: 30 Year Anniversary Report, 1964-1994 and publications describing CEW library holdings and materials from the Women in Science Program.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Center for the Education of Women.; University of Michigan. Center for Continuing Education of Women.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Women in Science Program.; University of Michigan. Center for Continuing Education of Women.
Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Brochures.; Calendars.; Flyers.; Journals.; Newsletters.; Proceedings.; Reports.
Publication Titles:
Center for the Education of Women, 30 year anniversary report, 1964-1994.; New research on women at the University of Michigan.; Non-traditional student attitudes and needs.; Survey of the graduate experience.; Women at the University of Michigan.
- Unit Publications
  Unit Publications (approximately 2 linear feet) includes bibliographies, brochures, calendars, directories, publication descriptions, discussion guides, flyers, press releases, programs, and questionnaires, each under their respective heading. CEW published several sets of papers (journals and proceedings) in conjunction with conferences and seminars that it sponsored. There is a nearly complete run of the center's newsletters Cornerstone: Center for the Education of Women and its predecessor Newsletter: Center for Continuing Education of Women. There are also scattered issues of the Center's first newsletter The University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women. "Print Books" includes various CEW compilations of its printed ephemera for each term or academic year, often including details such as paper type and duplication costs. Reports are broken down into "Histories and Retrospectives," which describe the activities and history of CEW, "Research Reports," that include studies on attitudes and needs of women at the University of Michigan, as well as a four-part series on the "Women at the University of Michigan." "Miscellaneous Reports" include reports generated from individual researchers at CEW, as well as reports that include arrange of topics.
  - Bibliographies
    - Careers for College Women: A Bibliography of Vocational Materials by Georgia P. Watermulder (Box 1)
    - A Directory of Research on Women, 1980, [1980] (Box 1)
    - Research Reports (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - CEW general circa 1970-2000 (Box 1)
    - Event Announcements and Invitations 1969-1999 (Box 1)
  - Calendars (Box 1)
  - CEW Publication Descriptions and Price Lists, ca 1968-1995 (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Women's resources (Box 1)
  - Discussion Guides
    - "Through My Lens" (Box 1)
    - "Turnabout" (Box 1)
    - "Two Women: Twenty Years" (Box 1)
  - Flyers and Information Sheets (Box 1)
  - Journals
    - New Research on Women, vol.1-5 (Box 1)
    - Sampler of Women's Studies, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Cornerstone: Center for the Education of Women, 1989-2004, 3 folders (Box 1)
      [Supersedes Newsletter: Center for Continuing Education of Women]
    - Newsletter: Center for Continuing Education of Women, 1971-1988, 5 folders (Box 1)
      [Supersedes The University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women]
    - The University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Press Releases (Box 1)
  - Printbooks and other Compilations of Printed Items
    - Printbooks 1983/84-1984/85 (Box 1)
    - Printbooks, 1988/89-December 1989 (Box 2)
  - Proceedings
    - Conversations with Returning Women Students, 1967 (Box 2)
    - New Careers in Community Service, 1968 (Box 2)
    - New Patterns of Employment, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Opportunities for Women Through Education, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Paving Passages for the Adult Woman: Workable Ideas in Women's Continuing Education, 1978 (Box 2)
      (Workshop Packet for the Center for Continuing Education of Women's Pre-Convention Workshop at the 1978 Annual Meeting of the National Association of Women Deans, Administrators, and Counselors [NAWDAC])
    - The Role of Women in Conflict and Peace, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Women in Action: Speeches and Panel Discussion of the Conference-Workshop, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Women on Campus, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Programs
    - Awards Programs 1976-1997 (Box 2)
    - General circa 1970-2001 (Box 2)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys 1968, 1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - CEW Histories and Retrospectives
      - Center for the Education of Women 30 Year Anniversary Report, 1964-1994, circa 1994 (Box 2)
      - Continuing Education of Women: a Memo and Suggestion for the University of Michigan, 1962 (Box 2)
      - The University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women, 1964-1977 A Report, 1978 (Box 2)
      - The University of Michigan Center for Continuing Education of Women, 1964-1984 A Report, 1984 (Box 2)
    - CEW Research Reports Series
      - CEW Research Report no. 16: Career and Family Issues of Professional Women Entering Non-Traditional Fields, 1984 (Box 2)
      - CEW Research Report no. 18: Some Correlates of Self-Esteem, Personal Control, and Occupational Attainment: An Overview of Findings from CEW Studies of Educated Women, 1985 (Box 2)
      - A Survey of the Graduate Experience: Sources of Satisfaction and Dissatisfaction Among Graduate Students at the University of Michigan, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Women Looking Ahead: Life and Career Planning for College Women, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Reports
      - Bridging Gender Divides Conference 2001 (Box 2)
      - CEW: Meeting the Needs of a Changing Population--A Follow-up Study of Participant Experiences at the Center, 1976, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Guidelines for Sponsors of CEW Administrative Interns,", 1985, 1995 (Box 2)
      - Michigan: A 'Smart State' for Women? Women and Higher Education, 2000 (Box 2)
      - The Michigan Women's Leadership Project: Leadership for Social Change, 1998 (Box 2)
      - Non-Traditional Student Attitudes and Needs: Summary Report of a Survey of Older Students, Winter 1980, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Professional Development Program for Wives of Foreign Students from the Third World: Report on the Pilot Project, 1984 (Box 2)
      - Third World Women at the University of Michigan: Personal and Professional Issues: Report on the Pilot Project, 1986 (Box 2)
      - Trends in Undergraduate Education: Proportions of Women and Part-Time Students, 1972 (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan Faculty Work-Life Study Report, 1999 (Box 2)
      - Value of Children in the United States: a New Approach to the Study of Fertility (Box 2)
      - Women at the University of Michigan: A Statistical Report on the Status of Women Students, Faculty and Staff on the Ann Arbor Campus, vol. 1-4 (Box 3)
      - Women in Mathematics and Physics: Inhibitors and Enhancers: Executive Summary, 1992 (Box 3)
      - Women's Agenda for the 1990s (Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Women's Issues). 1988 (Box 3)
- Sub Unit Publications
  Sub-Unit Publications include printed materials relating to the CEW Library and the "Women in Science Program". The majority of library related materials include topical bibliographies created by the library, as well as a folder of brochures, directories, and some library acquisition lists. The "Women in Science" Program includes brochures, flyers, programs, directories, resource lists, and a few newsletters related to the Program.
  - Library
    - Acquisition and Periodical Listings (Box 3)
    - Bibliographies
      - CEW Speakers and Conferences (Box 3)
      - Child Care (Box 3)
      - Counseling (Box 3)
      - Family and Marriage (Box 3)
      - Minorities (Box 3)
      - Vocational Indexes (Box 3)
      - Women and Education (Box 3)
      - Women and Employment (Box 3)
      - Women (general) (Box 3)
    - Brochures and Flyers (Box 3)
    - Directory ("Special Collections Independent of the University of Michigan Library System") 1977 (Box 3)
  - Women In Science
    - Brochures, Flyers, and Programs (Box 3)
    - Directories and Resource Lists (Box 3)
    - Newsletters (Box 3)
    - Reports (Box 3)